She makes dinner. She does windows. She reads bedtime
stories. She's a blessing... in disguise.
Mrs. Doubtfire is a comedy, drama, family film directed by Chris Columbus.
Loving but irresponsible dad Daniel Hillard, estranged from his exasperated spouse, is
crushed by a court order allowing only weekly visits with his kids.
When Daniel learns his ex needs a housekeeper, he gets
the job -- disguised as a British nanny.
Soon he becomes not only his children's best pal but the kind
of parent he should have been from the start.
Daniel Hillard / Mrs. Doubtfire, played by Robin Williams.
Miranda Hillard, played by Sally Field.
Lydia Hillard, played by Lisa Jakub.
Chris Hillard, played by Matthew Lawrence.
Natalie Hillard, played by Mara Wilson.
Stu, played by Pierce Brosnan.
Doubtfire is a 1993 American comedy-drama film directed by Chris Columbus, written by Randi Mayem
Singer and Leslie Dixon, based on the 1987 novel Madame Doubtfire, by Anne Fine.
The film was produced by Mark Radcliffe, Marsha Garces Williams and her
then-husband Robin Williams, who also starred in the lead role.
The film co-stars Sally Field, Pierce Brosnan,
Harvey Fierstein, and Robert Prosky.
It follows a recently divorced voice actor who disguises himself as an elderly
female housekeeper in order to spend time with his children.
Doubtfire was released in the United States by 20th
Century Fox on November 24, 1993.
It grossed $441.3 million on a $25 million budget, making it the
second-highest-grossing film of 1993 behind Jurassic Park.
While critical reception was mixed, the film won the Academy Award for Best Makeup,
and the Golden Globe Award for Best Motion Picture – Musical or Comedy.
Williams was awarded the Golden Globe Award for Best Actor
in a Motion Picture – Musical or Comedy.
The film explores themes of mask, parent child relationship, san
francisco, california, social worker, transvestite.
The tone is lighthearted and emotional.